Email: ae.mehda@gmail.com Phone/ Whatsapp: +213664726837 Git-Hub: github.com/Abdo-ME

ABDELHAK MEHDA

El oued - Algeria / +(213) 664726837

PROFILE

Creative Web Developer with 5 years of experience, leveraging JavaScript to build responsive websites, and specialized in ReactJS library, seeking to be full stack developer using NodJS and MongoDB in the back-end.

Providing high-impact web solutions for diverse industry organizations, aspiring to combine broad background with strong technical skills to excel as a Front-End Developer, I work well both independently and as part of a team.

EXPERIENCE

FEB 2017 – DEC 2021, ALGIERS – ALGERIA

FRONT-END DEVELOPER, TOP ACADEMIC SERVICES QUALITY (TASQ)

I had joined to **TASQ** as internship for three months, then they hired me as junior front-end developer, and after one year I specialized as React Js developer for the last three years, we created several projects for clients.

Major Accomplishments:

- Translated design team's UX wireframes and mockups into responsive, interactive features, using HTML/CSS, JavaScript and ReactJs (React, Redux).
- Build E-commerce sites and definition layouts for companies using React, Sass and other technologies.
- Maintaining an organized workflow using a project management tool using Git and Trello.
- Worked alongside a team of 2 developers to build TopFood APP for backend using NodeJs.
- Communicating technical issues in an understandable manner to the team.

JAN 2022 – PRESENT

FRONT-END DEVELOPER, FREELANCER

I have developed and fixed bugs for many web applications with HTML/CSS, BOOTSTRAP, React JS and Node JS ... etc.

Major Accomplishments:

- Built single-page applications with JavaScript on a custom-built framework
- Modified websites for front and backend using NodeJs, Express, and ReactJS.
- Applied media queries to create responsive website across different size of screens.
- Supported existing applications like adding new features to a webpage, data corrections, and development issues.

Email: ae.mehda@gmail.com phone: +213 664726837 git-hub: https://github.com/Abdo-ME

EDUCATION

SEP 2010 - JUL 2015

MASTRER OF INDUSTRIAL SYSTEM ENGINEERING, UNIVERSITY OF MOHAMED KHIDER

I graduated from the university in 2015 with a master's degree in industrial systems engineering

2016 - PRESENT

FRONT-END DEVELOPER ONLINE CERTIFICATES

I really enjoyed teaching myself coding with online courses. I found all what I need to learn from platforms like Coursera, Udemy and Youtube.

SKILLS

DEV SKILLS

- HTML5/CSS3/BOOTSTRAP
- JavaScript (ES6)
- JQuery
- Sass
- ReactJS
- Redux Redux-Toolkit
- CONTEXT API
- Expert in responsive
- Git/Git-Hub
- Trello
- NodJS
- Express
- MongoDB (Basics)
- Photoshop knowledge(Basics)

SOFT SKILLS

- Learning Ability
- Good and effective communication with Teamwork
- Problem-solving ability